So this is an off-topic video for the patrons, there
Так це таке офтоп відео для патронів
will be two of them, one about how I
буде їх два одне про те як я за все
record everything and one about what happens on
записую і одне про те що відбувається на
my desktop and this is the first one, actually,
моєму робочому столі і це перше
about what happens on
насправді про те що відбувається на
my desktop, how it all looks.
моєму робочому столі як це все виглядає
I think I'll go through all
Я думаю я пройдусь по всім
aspects of my setup. It looks quite
аспектам свого сетапу виглядає досить
interesting and let's take it in order. The main
цікаво і давайте по порядку основний
challenge for me is that I have one
челендж в мене це те що в мене є один
monitor and that one. Well, the small one can't be
монітор а той Ну той маленький можна не
considered some kind of super monitor. The big ones
вважати як якимось там супермонітором
are such an additional thing that I don't
велики це така додаткова штука якою я не
often use. I ordered it on Aliexpress
часто користуюсь замовив на аліекспресі
and maybe I'll hang it closer to the
і можливо я повішу його поближче до
camera. I hung it up not so long ago. I
камери от я її Повісив не так давно
filmed it on my phone before and I have a
раніше знімав на телефон і в мене є
system unit that is quite powerful. Let's
системник який досить потужний Давайте
start with it. It has a 3090 viddha, 128
почнемо з нього в ньом 3090 віддха 128
GB of RAM, a
ГБ оперативы
5950x imd processor. Then you can
5950x imdшний процесор потім можна
see this. The water cooling is
побачити оце от охолодження Водяне яке
for the processor, which is sold in
для процесора от яке продається в
principle assembled. That is, it's not some kind of
принципі зібране Тобто це не якийсь
custom and I have two essdeshins there, each
Кастом і в мене там два ессдешника по
terabyte M2. I once  I put a 980ti in the Samsung
терабайту М2 Колись я ставив в самсунгі
and then had to buy another
980ті і довелось потім докуповувати ще
2-terabyte SSD, a regular 2.5-
двохтерабайтовий ссдшник звичайний 2,5
inch one, this one is standard, in order to
дюйми оцей от стандартний для того щоб
write videos that I edit, proxy
писати туди відео які я монтую прокі
files, and so on, because they take up quite a
файли і так далі бо вони займають досить
lot of space. My monitor is 32 inches
багато місця так монітор в мене 32 дюйми
from Lenovo. I am very happy with this
від Lenovo Я дуже задоволений цим
monitor. Now I will tell you why. But before
монітором зараз розповім чому але перед
that, I will show you another monitor that I
тим я покажу вам ще один монітор який в
have on my desk. It is an old JVC video monitor
мене є на столі це старий відеомонітор
specifically for
JVC для спеціально для систем
video surveillance systems. It used to be there, but I
відеоспостереження він колись був але я
use it for retro gaming. But
його використовую для ретрогеймінгу але
it is possible. I will tell you separately. The main
це можливо розповім окремо так основний
challenge with the monitor,
челендж з монітором
speakers, keyboard and mouse is that
колонками клавіатурою і мишкою в тому що
I have a system administrator. I have
в мене є системник в мене є
two laptops. One laptop here is a volunteer Carbon X1
два ноутбука один ноутбук тут Carbon X1
conditionally for volunteer
волонтерський умовно під волонтерські
tasks and a 16-inch MacBook for Google
задачі і macbук 16 дюймів підгуглові
tasks. Which also has to be somehow
задачі Який теж має бути якось
connected to the monitor, to the camera, to the
під'єднаний до монітора до камери до
keyboard, to the mouse. Let me show you how
клавіатури До мишки давайте покажу як
everything is connected to me now. If
воно в мене тепер все під'єднано якщо
you look, you can see that the speakers
подивитися то можнабачити що колонки
they are connected to the monitor this is my
воне підключени до монітора це в мене
camera this is Logitech whistle for mouse and
камера це Logitech свисток на мишку і
keyboard uh this is just some
клавіатуру е-е Це просто якийсь
additional USB and then you can see I
додатковий USB і потім можна побачити в
still have a Nintendo Switch here
мене тут ще стоїть Nintendo Switch до
three devices connected to the monitor below
монітора внизу підключено три пристрої
one displayport is the system unit type-c
один дисплейпорт - це системник type-c -
is laptops and HDMI is the Nintendo Switch
це ноутбуки і HDMI - це Nintendo Switch
And now I will show how I switch between all this
І зараз я покажу як я все між цим
Let's start with the option
перемикаюсь Давайте почнемо з варіанту
when I use a laptop when I
коли я використовую ноутбук коли я
use a laptop I just
використовую ноутбук Я просто
switch to zunderbolt switched and
перемикаюсь на zunderbolt перемикнувся і
conditionally use a laptop and I have the
умовно користуюсь ноутбуком і в мене
keyboard and mouse going through the same cable
через той самий кабель іде і клавіатура
Well, in fact everything works
і мишка Ну то по суті все все працює
now and the camera but when I switch
тепер і камера але коли я перемикаюсь
for example to dis display port Here
наприклад на disдисплей пор Тут виникає
the question arises how is it all connected via USB and it is
питання як це все під'єднано по USB і це
all connected via USB with a USB cable to
все по USB під'єднано USB кабелем до
the computer there is a separate cable it is separately
комп'ютера там окремий кабель він окремо
inserted into the monitor and here I can
вставляється в на монітор і тут я можу
select Source for USB and it will be either
вибрати Source для USB і це буде або
Thunderbolt or USB Type B That is this
Thunderbolt або USB Type B Тобто це
switching where
перемикання куди Мають бути підє
all USB devices that are
під'єднані всі USB пристрої які
connected to the phone or to should be connected  laptop
під'єднані до телефону або до лептопа
or in fact to my system unit when I
або по суті до мого системника коли
need to switch between laptops I
треба перемикнутися між лептопами то я
just pull the cable from one
просто перевитягаю кабель з одного
laptop plug it into another and that's all
ноутбука вставляю в інший і оце все що
I had to do to
мені треба було зробити щоб
switch but there's even more I
перемикнутися але є навіть більше в мене
have a Nintendo Switch which I showed Which Now
є Nintendo swich які я показував Який
I'm going to disconnect the gmbd basically I can
Ось я зараз відключу gмbд по суті я можу
start it and now I can
його запустить і тепер я можу
switch to hdmi1 and And I will
перемикнутися на hdmi1 і І в мене буде
Where is my Nintendo Switch Yes there is a Nintendo
Де мій Nintendo Switch Так є Nintendo
Switch Well accordingly the sound is also
Switch Ну і відповідно звук теж
output to the speakers Now let's move on
виводиться на колонки Тепер давайте далі
Okay I also have a keyboard that I
Окей В мене є ще така клавіатура яку я
use for editing I just
використовую для монтажу Я її просто
connect it with this USB cable it has
підключаю оцим от USB кабелем в неї є
Bluetooth but I connect it just with a USB
Bluetooth але я підключаю її просто USB
cable I really
кабелем клавіатура мені супер
like the keyboard and about how I write a video I'll
подобається і про те як пишу відео я
shoot a separate video I also have a
зніму окреме відео також в мене є тут
ggamepad from PlayStation 5 which I
gгеймпад від PlayStation 5 який я
connect too How with this same cable if
підключаю теж Як цим самим кабелем якщо
I want to play something under Windows and on
хочу щось пограти під windowнoy і на
this same computer I have Linux and
цьому самому комп'ютері в мене є Linux і
wna further I have such a thing for that
wнa далі В мене є отака штука для того
to switch scenes during streaming is
щоб перемикати сцени під час стрімінгу
also very convenient and there is some additional
теж дуже зручно і є якесь додаткове
light for the green
світло для зеленого
background so that there is better backlighting let's
фону щоб була краща підсвітка давайте
now see how it all looks
тепер подивимося як це все виглядає
from behind what we see we see Oh such an
ззаду що ми бачимо ми бачимо О такий
interesting device is still on the table
цікавий пристрій ще на столі
it's just a lot of all sorts of chargers
е просто багато всяких там зарядок в
I have connected some it has its
мене підключено якихось це він з
own USB ports in short everything so that you
власними USB портами короче все щоб
can connect it there
можна було туди підключити тут зверху
wirelessly from above I also have this
бездратово також в мене От є отакий от
air filter that works in different
фільтр для повітря який працює в різних
modes and automatically usually but now
режимах і автоматично зазвичай але зараз
it was turned off just so it wouldn't make noise and
він був вимкнений щоб просто не шумів і
maybe I'll move it somewhere and
можливо я його кудись переставлю і
let's see my interesting setup for streams
давайте подивимося мій цікавий сетап для
or for recording in general
стрімів чи взагалі для запису Нещодавно
I recently added Oh such a fan just so that there
я додав О такий вентилятор просто щоб
was better cooling because my
було краще охолодження бо моя ця камера
Fuji xe4 camera was constantly overheating in 4K there
Fuji xe4 постійно перегрівалося в 4К там
for 20 minutes was enough now I can
на 20 хвилин вистачало тепер я можу
write videos normally it's all being filmed further I have
нормально писати відео це все знімається
this microphone from above you see I have a green background a little bit of
такий мікрофон зелений фон трішечки
some acoustic foam if
якогось там акустичного поролону якщо
you look at all these desks from behind you
подивитися на ці всі парти ззаду То
can see these cables go  to the camera
можна побачити це ідуть кабеля до камери
USB micro HDMI but what's more interesting is that
USB micro HDMI але що ще цікаво що цей
I really like this table it's a big
стіл мені супер подобається він велика
tabletop high from the base you can
столешніца високий від осно можна
make it higher and I often
зробити його вище і я часто цим
use it well that is the whole whole whole this
користуюся ну тобто вся вся вся ця
structure
конструкція
rises completely and in principle I
піднімається повністю і я в принципі в
work in this standing mode very often
такому режимі стоячи дуже часто працюю
just to have some additional
щоб просто якесь було додаткове
load Oh I have such a guy what else do I have
навантаження О такий в мене чувачок є що
this thing This is enet and I
далі ще є в мене отака штука Це еnet і я
connected it to the iPhone in order to have
підключав це до Айфону для того щоб була
less or more stable delay when I was
менша або стабільніша затримка коли я
recording the video Well and actually when I
записував відео Ну і власне коли я
record a video for YouTube I lower the
записую відео для Ютуба я опускаю
table as low as possible so that the
максимально низько стіл наскільки це
camera is at
можливо для того щоб камера була на
eye level That's how it works I had to
рівні очей Ось і так воно працює я мав
record
записати
my retro gaming setup this is straight top So
мій ретроігровий сетап це прям топ Так
now I'll press pause so that I can
зараз я натисну паузу для того щоб можна
tell a little about it this is a real
було трішечки про це розповісти це прям
feature that is these monitors they
фішка тобто ці монітори їх досить
were quite difficult to find and buy in the States
складно було знайти і купити в Штатах
they are generally priceless these monitors are
вони взагалі безцінні ці монітори
used they
використовують
were used before in
використовувались раніше в системах
video surveillance systems in medicine or on
відеоспостереження в медицині або на
television this monitor
телебаченні цей монітор власне
was actually used on television I
використовувався на телебаченні я його
found it  on the KSU and it can do it, well, super super.
знайшов на КСУ і він вміє ну супер супер
I don't know how to show you the picture here is
Я не знаю як вам показати картиночка тут
just top-notch and it's not the same picture when
просто топова і це не така картинка коли
you connect a raspberry piie or
ви підключаєте rastberry piie чи
run the emulator on a regular LCD.
запускаєте емулятор на звичайном LCD
If you run it here and here, it will be a
якщо запустити тут і тут то це буде ну
huge difference. I bought this expansion board in Spain.
величезна різниця я докупив в Іспанії
This
Отакі Такі
expansion board accepts
от плату розширення яка приймає
analog RGB, but there is no analog in the raspberry piie.
аналоговий оцей rgb але в raspberry piie
I bought this board in
немає аналогового ні плату докупив в
Britain and in Spain I bought this thing.
Британії а в Іспанії докупив оцю штуку
It does this. Some enthusiast has a very
це робить Якийсь ентузіаст дуже
cool thing for the raspberry pi. You connect it
прикольну штуку для rasberpie ви
and it allows you to output
підключаєте і вона дозволяє вам вивести
analog
аналоговий
RGB output to the raspberry piie and
rgb output на з rasberry piie і
connect it either to a TV that
підключити або до телевізора який це
supports it, or to the monitor itself, like
підтримує ну або власне до монітора от
in my case. And this is just a top-notch
як в моєму випадку І це просто топова
picture with the raspberry piie with analog
картинка з rasberry piie з аналоговим
RGB output. RGB SCRP. With this board, with this
rgb виходом rgb scр з цей платой з цим
monitor, you get a top-notch setup.
монітором виходить прям топовий топовий
And I have this ggeymepd, which you
сетап ну і в мене є оцей gгеймepд який
may have already seen on the video, which is in
можливо вже побачили на відео який в
the style of old gamepads from Sgav, which
стилі сгавських старих геймпадів який
works great with this
просто супер працює з з цією
design, if  If you have any
конструкцією всією якщо є якісь будь-які
questions, ask, I will answer.
питання питайте буду відповідати